[keys jangling]
[engine starts]
[Jerry]
This is a 1967 Volvo 1800S.
Volvo's a very straightforward
Swedish company.
For example, the official
Volvo paint-code name
for this color is red.
It has a four-cylinder,
115-horsepower engine
that goes 109 miles per hour
and will last forever.
A guy who lives
right near where I grew up
on Long Island, named Irv Gordon,
drove one of these three million miles
and he's still not tired of it.
I've been driving it for five minutes,
and I totally get it.
I wanna do three million miles.
[phone ringing]
-[Tina] Hello?
-[Jerry] Hello?
-[Jerry] Tina?
-[Tina] Jerry?
-[Jerry] How are you?
-[Tina] Good, how are you?
-[Jerry] Good.
Seeing as though we are so close together,
geographically...
I was wondering if you would
like to meet me
for a cup of coffee.
-[Tina] Yes, please.
-[Jerry] On my way.
Hi, I'm Jerry Seinfeld,
and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
Today my guest is Tina Fey,
the first female head writer
of Saturday Night Live
and is the creator and star of the
million-Emmy-award-winning 30 Rock.
[Tina] Ooh, it's pretty.
Is this a real seat belt?
It is kind of, yeah.
You pull it up like that...
I like that this is just like a metal ring
like you would tie a horse to.
[Jerry] Is that a wig?
Or is that the greatest
hair an old woman has ever had?
-Oh, that might be a wig.
-I don't mind a wig.
-You don't mind a wig?
-No.
[Jerry] I like healthy hair.
I don't care where it's from
or whose it was originally.
[Tina] I've been
on the Upper West Side a long time.
If you walk around the Upper West Side,
you will never ever see
a truly good-looking person.
If you're on 14th Street, you may be,
like, "That girl's a model."
-[Jerry] Oh, I hate how true that is.
-Yeah.
Mister, what year?
-[Tina] '67.
-'67?
Can I be on your show so
I can make some little buck?
I'm tired of driving the cab.
[Jerry] Yeah, but this show
is still just more driving.
One of the things I like about you,
besides everything,
is, like myself, you enjoy eating
-things you're not supposed to eat.
-Yeah.
-Because, it's like little mini vacations
-in your stressful day, right?
-Exactly.
Nights where I win an Emmy,
and then be like,
"What's my food treat gonna be?"
Like the Emmy was not a treat.
The only reward for anything is food.
[Jerry] I don't know if you get it
or not, but this car is you.
-It's sensible, but fun.
-But it's a little fun.
-[Jerry] So you've never lived in LA?
-[Tina] Nope.
Because I don't drive.
-You don't drive?
-I don't have a license anymore.
-You don't ever drive a car?
-Nope.
How long do you think
you can last like this?
What if you have to get somewhere?
What if you have to go get some food?
-Well, it's New York City.
-Is a car, to you, just like an abacus?
"I know people use them, I don't."
Is that what a car is?
This is like Twitter to me.
[Tina] I had to drive
in one of those commercials,
They're like, "Just pull up
and you get out and just run out..."
And I was like, "Yeah, yeah."
Not telling them I couldn't really do it.
I pulled up and I forgot
to put the car in park
and then got out and ran in front of it,
and the whole crew was like,
"Wait, wait, wait!"
I almost ran myself over.
[both laughing]
-[Jerry] Do you like coffee?
-[Tina] I do.
-Are you in the mood for coffee?
-Yes.
[Tina] People keep saying,
"You miss 30 Rock?" I'm like, "No."
I wanna have an office that I go to,
and I make a coffee,
-work for 40 minutes...
-So far our lives are exactly the same.
...of thinking about something, and then,
"Should we walk out to lunch?"
Then you go out to lunch.
Then you're like, "Oh,
the kids will be home from school soon.
Let's wrap it up."
[both chuckle]
[inaudible]
We'll leave you to the menu?
We have one more on this end.
Any juice you'd like,
carrot, beet, apple, cinnamon?
[Jerry] "Guanabana/soursop."
I haven't had that in a while.
"Wheat puffs juice"?
You ever heard of that?
A wheat milkshake? Yeah, we better try it.
-Two? Okay.
-Yeah, two.
-A wheat milkshake?
-Is that what we just got?
I think we... [laughs]
[Tina] Oh, good, we got two.
[Jerry] Everything's different up here,
Tina.
It tastes like something my eight-year-old
would say, "I invented this."
-What is it?
-It's wheat puffs. It's cereal and...
-It says wheat puffs.
-Wheat puffs?
[Tina] I'm sure it's just a box of cereal.
-It's cereal made into a beverage.
-[Jerry laughs]
[Jerry] We know what it is.
The question is, why it is.
-To keep the elderly alive.
-[both laugh]
So tell me what you would love
to find yourself doing in a year.
I'd like to write another movie.
'Cause I only wrote one movie.
It's hard to have
that much fire in your belly.
You do something like Seinfeld,
you do it once, and it's thrilling
and you're kind of in it together,
but once you've done it
and you know how much work it is,
you can't fake that.
I mean, like, I'm satisfied.
I never thought I would do that.
-You know?
-That's how I feel. That's how I feel.
-Yeah.
-I don't mind-- I just looked in the lens.
What, am I on The Office?
God damn that little Ricky Gervais, man.
He's got it figured out.
He never makes more than six of anything
and he sells it to the entire world.
-He writes like six episodes.
-Yeah.
And he's like, "I'm a genius."
Wait, how many episodes of Seinfeld
did you write?
-180
-180, yeah.
But that thing is where season is like 13.
Louis does that. Louis does, like,
13 and then he takes two years off.
Oh, yeah. Come on.
'Cause when the... the 22 is...
you start to... Sometimes it's the middle
where you start to go crazy
-Yeah.
-Sometimes good things come out.
-Weird episodes.
-Yeah, right.
But, also, sometimes you get pneumonia.
It was the back nine,
was the backbreaker for us right?
Yeah the back nine.
You could kind of figure out
the first ten over the summer.
-You pull three more out of nowhere.
-Right. Yep.
-And then the back nine is just...
-I know... [blows raspberry]
You're Sandra Bullock in Gravity.
Yeah. [chuckles]
I always wish I could be a stand-up.
-I tried it, like, three times in Chicago.
-Oh, really?
[Tina]
I remember, compared to improv,
it was so much scarier,
and so much more thrilling,
'cause if you did get a laugh,
it was all yours.
-Right.
-But then when you were flop-sweaty
that was also all you.
The thing about stand-up,
it's a bit of a brutality
that you have to have.
I would venture to say
you're missing that piece.
That reminds me of
when I first moved here.
My mom would say,
"Your cousin has a job
handing out fragrance in Bloomingdale's.
Why don't you just get a job
being one of the girls
who gives out fragrance
in Bloomingdale's?"
Like, "Mom, are you gonna make me explain
I'm not pretty enough
to hand out fragrance cards
in Bloomingdale's?"
My cousin was tall and had blond hair,
and she was good at makeup,
and personable.
I'm none of those things.
[both laugh]
That doesn't come in the comedy kit.
"Tall, personable and good at makeup."
-That person is never gonna be funny.
-[laughs]
-Your youngest one is...
-Eight.
Oh, that's how old my oldest is.
So, I have eight and two.
-Two girls?
-Two girls.
Sometimes my daughter would
come to set and I'd be shooting a scene
where I'm just pretending to be
married to Steve Carell.
They're immediately like,
"What is this, who is this gentleman?"
[Jerry laughs]
I'm like, "This is Mr. Carell."
She was always the same way
with Alec, too. She'd be like this.
And he would be like,
"Hi," so warm to her.
And she' be like, "I don't know about you.
My mother seems to spend
a lot of time with you."
Your kids, where are they on Santa Claus?
Well, we're Jewish.
I was obsessed with Christmas trees
as a kid.
I would say to my mother,
"Can we get one this year?"
She said, "No. We can have
a Hanukkah bush."
I go, "Oh, fantastic,
when are we gonna get that?"
And she says, "Well, it's out front."
Yeah.
I'd go, "Where?"
She opens the door, "That one.
That's it."
"Are we gonna decorate it?"
"No, not this year."
"Not this year."
'Cause I find that certain duties
fall with certain parents.
Like, my husband
is more on the barf patrol.
I can do it. He's better at it.
I'm in charge of feces.
All the household feces
are my purview.
I like "feces" and "purview"
in the same sentence.
I like that a lot.
Who do you think, of the two of us,
is more opaque to the public?
-I don't know.
-I think you would win that.
I don't ever look
at stuff online about myself.
'Cause, obviously,
it's, like, such a terrible idea.
But I went online the other day
because there was a picture of Amy.
She was doing some nice thing
where she works with Worldwide Orphans.
I was reading the thing.
And I'm like, "This is so nice."
There's always one person that says,
"I love her. She's the opposite
of Tina Fey, who seems like
she'd never help another person
if her life depended on it."
What? What is it? Is it my face?
Why do you think that?
You should have to have a license
to be on Twitter.
When 30 Rock ended, they were like,
"What do you want?"
"I wanna be in charge
of the Twitter licenses."
So, how would you get the license?
You would give me 10 samples
of what you might want to talk about,
and I'd talk to you about whether
that was something we needed to know.
Why is it that everyone
needs to have an audience
for, like, every moment of their life?
The question you're asking is,
"I picked up a rock the other day
and there were all these insane insects
-and I yelled, 'What are you all doing?'"
-[laughs]
-"Stop doing that!"
-"Get organized.
-And behave!"
-"Be birds!"
As if it's an intellectual choice.
[Tina] There was a guy in college
I sort of dated.
I remember going to lunch with him.
He was like, "You, uh,
you really eat a lot."
And I just took it as a compliment.
[Jerry]
Have you ever had a Cronut?
Oh, I've heard about these,
I've read about the Cronut.
-Is it good?
-Yeah.
So, I found out,
there's a place in the village,
they have one Cronut left.
-Are you serious?
-I'm serious.
-It may be dented, I don't know.
-I would be interested in any of that.
Great. Let's go downtown.
Where the good-looking people are.
[Jerry] Now, look at this.
[Tina] See, something you will not see
on the Upper West Side.
A model posing in a Porsche.
That's a fake Porsche Spyder.
So, they're doing their show with a car
as we drive by doing our show with a car.
[both chuckle]
[Jerry] What do you buy
that's too expensive for what it is?
-What would be, like, an indulgence?
-An indulgence? Uh...
-I don't know...
-You're squirming.
I'm squirming, I don't have that many!
-How can I answer this and stay opaque?
-Yeah. [chuckles]
There it is. Dominique Ansel,
that's the guy.
[Tina] Your church.
[Jerry] Hello, Dominique.
It's nice to meet you.
-I'm Jerry. This is Tina.
-[Dominique] Hi.
[inaudible]
-Is there something you wanna try here?
-Everything, yeah.
-[Tina] Call an ambulance in 15 minutes.
-[Jerry laughs]
Make sure he's got an insulin pack.
[Jerry] Wow!
Jesus.
All right, here we go.
"She was never seen again."
Is there gonna be chains of Cronut stores?
I wonder how he's gonna...
That's interesting,
'cause we know what
any American would do.
-Wreck it. Just blow it out.
-Blow it out.
Pour it every which way but loose.
But he's French, so instead,
he will take a 70-week vacation...
[both chuckle]
...and never make it again.
I love that story of the date.
What did the guy say?
He was like, "You really eat a lot."
And I took it as a compliment, like,
"He knows I'm really
kind of real," like...
And did you go out
on a second date with him?
I never went on a real date with him.
It was always just, like,
"You're around. Wanna get a sandwich?"
It was exactly what you hope your daughter
has too much dignity
to ever participate in.
I bet you all the women,
and you certainly know
more comedy women than I do.
It's a struggle for them
to balance their feminine projections
with their comedic goals.
Like, if I do a talk show,
I gotta have my stories together,
and I got to try to look okay.
Yeah.
But some people work in coal mines,
so, actually...
[Jerry] I wonder if there are any really
progressive coal mines.
[Tina] We wanna be like Google.
We want people
to have fun on their breaks.
-We're gonna have ping-pong.
-Yoga.
And then a cave-in.
[both laugh]
-Oh, this is the greatest show ever.
-[laughs]
I would commit to 22 episodes
a year of this.
Yeah.
[Tina]
I don't have a key to my apartment.
'Cause we're in that kind of building
where the doorman lets you up.
Tina Fey, no key, no car.
Mental child.
Like this girl. She's not thinking,
"How am I gonna get home?"
"I'll just keep throwing these pillows.
I can make as big a mess as I want."
"I'm adorable. I'm eight foot tall
and adorable."
[Jerry] "I'm gonna spray some cards
and hand them out at Bloomingdale's."
[Tina] She could book that job
at Bloomingdale's like that.
[Tina] One time, I did a two-day
rewrite of a movie.
It was Chris Rock and he wanted
to bring in a few comedy writers.
-Yeah.
-It was me and Louis,
a couple of Chris' friends...
But I just remember
Louis being really funny.
[Jerry]
I'm actually tingling at this moment.
Because Louis told me this story,
and you know where he told it to me?
Right there, at Chelsea Pier,
two weeks ago.
-This is a good watch for you.
-This is a gift from Chris Rock.
-Oh, really?
-I spent one day
in a hotel suite
with him and some other writers.
He paid us 5,000 bucks each,
fed us really well, and it was just fun.
[Tina] He also gave us each
a beautiful Rolex watch.
[Louise] Inside, it's inscribed,
and it says,
"Thanks for your help, mother [bleeps]."
I don't know if he wrote that
in Tina Fey's.
It's engraved, and it says,
-"Thanks for your help, mother [bleeps]."
-Right.
Which, I just like that somebody
had to go to the Rolex store
and ask for five of those
engraved that way.
I almost wore it today, actually.